现在我们已经定义了其中的一些，我要走了
Now that we've defined a few of these, I'm gonna go
进一步解释一下这是如何作为幺半群工作的。
a little further and explain how this works as a monoid.
然后我们将看到它如何应用于函子。
And then we'll see how it applies to functors.
然后我们会做一些练习并在它们上面建立一个小库。
And then we'll do some exercises and build a little library on them.
但是幺半群只是一个半群，
But monoids are just a semigroup,
有身份，所以
with an identity, so
幺半群是一个半群，幺半群，
a monoid is a semigroup, monoid,
半群，加上一个身份，好吗？
semigroup, plus an identity, okay?
你问了身份函数。
And you asked about the identity function.
这是一个身份函数。
Here's an identity function.
我们将在界面中称这个为空，但是
We're going to call this one empty in the interface, but
这只是一个身份函数。
it's just an identity function.
所以产品，如果我称它为空将是一个。
So products, if I call it empty will be one.
以及原因
And the reason for
也就是说，如果我将任何东西乘以一，我就会得到那个东西，对吗？
that is if I multiply anything plus one I get that thing back, right?
我必须把它放在一个产品中。
I have to put it in a product.
我们走了。
There we go.
让我们看看这里是如何工作的。
Let's see how that works down here.
所以如果我有我的产品，concat products 10，
So if I have my products, concat products 10,
我要把产品 10 拿出来。
I'm gonna get product 10 out.
这只是一个身份函数。
It's just an identity function.
因此，我可以说 product.empty，而不是专门用于 1。
And so instead of being specialized to 1, I can say product.empty.
现在，我可以用 10 和
Now, I can concat that with 10 and
我正在编程一个接口，而不是一个特定的值。
I am programming to an interface, not a specific value.
让我们对 sum 做同样的事情。
Let's do the same thing for sum.
sum 的身份是什么？
What's the identity for sum?
我会说 sums.empty 函数的总和为零，对吗？
I'll say sums.empty function is sum of zero, right?
这就是身份。
So that'll be the identity.
如果我将其与任何其他总和联系起来，我会得到零。
If I concat that with any other sum, I get zero.
为什么这很重要？
Why does this matter?
有没有人对为什么身份在这里很重要有任何猜测？
Does anybody have any guesses on why the identity matters here?
&gt;&gt; 空值。
&gt;&gt; Null values.
&gt;&gt; 完全正确。
&gt;&gt; That's exactly right.
Kaylee 定理有一些很酷的东西，你可以部分应用
There's some cool stuff with Kaylee's theorem where you can partially apply
一切以他的身份，并获得这些很酷的懒惰功能等等。
everything with his identity and get these cool lazy functions and whatnot.
但主要是在我们的日常生活中，如果我要遍历一个列表并将其缩小，
But mainly In our day to day, if I was to run through a list and reduce it down,
如果我没有起始值，我将得到一个空值或未定义值。
if I don't have a starting value, I'm gonna get a null or an undefined.
但是如果我有一个起始值，这两个对应于reduce。
But if I have a starting value, these these two correspond to reduce.
让我们来看看。
So let's take a look at that.
所以我们有一个包含 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 的列表。
So we have a list of 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
我们减少了。
And we reduce that.
我们得到累加器和每个数字。
And we get the accumulator and each number.
让我们继续说我会把这个数字加起来。
And let's just go ahead and say I will put the number in a sum.
我将把它连接起来，
And I'm going to concat that with,
我将从那里的累加器连接数开始。
I'll start with the accumulator concat number there.
好，太棒了。
Okay, great.
所以这里将要发生的事情是有希望的，我们将得到所有这些数字的总和。
So what's gonna happen here is hopefully, we'll get the sum of all these numbers.
让我们运行它。
And let's run that.
好吧，我们不会。
All right, we won't.
[笑] 看到 at.concat 不是一个函数。
[LAUGH] See at.concat is not a function.
好吧，我想它不会开始。
All right, I guess it doesn't start.
&gt;&gt; 您必须将 sum 作为次要参数并减少。
&gt;&gt; You gottta put sum as the secondary argument and reduce.
是的，这行不通。
Yeah, it's not gonna work.
好吧，让我们去做吧。
Well, let's do it.
让我们把它们都放在这里。
Let's put them all over here.
让我们把它们映射成一个总和。
Let's just map them into a sum.
然后我们将减少它们。
And then we'll reduce them all.
这很有意义。
That makes a lot of sense.
好的，现在我们有一堆总和。
Okay, so now we have a bunch of sums.
大家都很开心。
Everybody's happy.
但是我们会在这里看到，我们没有给 reduce 它的空值。
But we'll see here that we're not giving reduce its empty value.
我们只是给它一个清单。
We're just giving it a list.
所以在这种情况下的总和列表。
So a list of sums in this case.
我们得到 15 个。
And we get 15.
但是如果我们给它一个空列表，会发生什么？
But if we give it an empty list, what's gonna happen?
简直要炸了
It's just gonna blow up.
原因是减少了没有初始值的空数组。
And the reason for that is reduce of an empty array with no initial value.
所以我们没有什么可以返回的。
So we have nothing to return.
如果我们给它一个一无所有的清单，我们将一无所获。
If we give it a list of nothing, we have nothing in return.
但是如果我们给它一个列表，我们从 sum.empty 开始。
But if we give it a list, we start with sum.empty.
我们走了。
There we go.
我们实际上可以取回 0。
We can actually get 0 back.
所以我们有一种方法可以在我们的程序中使用一个表示好的初始值，
So we have a way to proceed in our program with an initial value that says okay,
即使我们现在没有任何数据要处理，
even though we didn't have any data to process right now,
我们仍然可以为您提供某种价值。
we can still provide you some kind of value.
你可以继续。
And you can continue on.
所以就像这里的空值一样爆炸。
So just blowing up being like here's a null.
所以，我们可以在这里做一件事，这确实发生了
So, one thing we can do here, this actually happens
相当多的是，我们想把东西放到幺半群中。
quite a bit is that we want to put stuff into a monoid.
然后调用 concat。
And then call concat.
并从空开始。
And start with empty.
这整件事几乎是多余的。
This whole thing is almost redundant.
这实际上是我总结整个列表的方式，对吗？
This is actually how I would sum up a whole list, right?
这是我如何获得整个列表的产品。
Here's how I would get the products of a whole list.
我只是把它全部放在一个产品中。
I just put it all into a product.
然后我会浏览一个列表并得到它们的产品。
And then I'd run through a list and get the product of them.
如果我有一堆真假真假怎么办？
What if I have a bunch of true, false, true?
让我把它放到下一行，这样你就可以看到发生了什么。
Let me break this onto the next line so you can see what's going on.
但好吧，让我们继续
But all right, let's go ahead and
将它们放入任何并说嘿，有没有空的？
put those into an any and say hey does any have an empty?
让我们来看看。
Let's see.
什么可以作为任何人的身份？
What would act as identity for any?
如果我说任何真连接任何假，
If I said any true concat any false,
这将返回任何 true。
that would return any true.
好的，所以这有点像右侧的身份，任何虚假。
All right, so that acts kind of like an identity on the right side, any false.
如果我说 any false concat any true 那将是右侧的任何 true。
If I said any false concat any true that would be any true on the right side.
好的，那么任何虚假或虚假呢？
Okay, so what about any false any false?
&gt;&gt; 那将是错误的。
&gt;&gt; That would be false.
好的，因此，如果这是
Okay, so therefore, if this was
空我会得到任何假的，假的。
empty I would get any false, false.
没错，真假。
Yep, true and false.
抱歉，我只是在脑子里想出这个真值表。
Sorry, I'm just working this truth tables out in my head.
所以让我们试试看。
So let's try that.
我会说 any.empty 是一个函数加上任何错误。
I would say any.empty is a function plus any false.
因此，如果您在此过程中遇到任何 true，它会将其返回。
So if you hit any trues along the way, it'll return it back.
但这充当了身份。
But this acts as an identity.
如果我再给它任何真假，任何真回。
If I give it any true and false again any true back.
如果我给它任何虚假的虚假得到任何虚假的回报，身份。
If I give it any false false get any false back, identity.
很酷，所以我们有。
Cool, so we have that.
我们也可以用 and 做所有事情。
We can alternatively do all with the and.
创建，然后这将是全部。
Create, and then this will be all.
让我们继续为所有人定义一个空的。
Let's go ahead and define an empty for all.
而这恰恰相反。，都是如此。
And that would just be opposite., all true.
如果有什么是假的，它只会翻转开关并且是假的。
And if anything is false, it will just flip the switch and be false.
所以现在我们可以减少这个，说这些是真的吗？
So now we can reduce this, say are any of these true?
这是一次又一次完全相同的模板，对吗？
And this is the same exact template again and again and again, right?
如果我们运行这个，我们会得到 true，因为它们中的任何一个都是 true。
If we run this, we get true because any of them are true.
他们所有人呢？
How about all of them?
他们都是真的吗？
Are all of them true?
这不是真的。
That's not true.
那是假的。
That's false.
里面有假货。
There's a false in there.
我们摆脱它。
We get rid of it.
那么它们都会是真的。
Then they will all be true.
伟大的。
Great.